We are not alone.
Close Encounters of the Third Kind is a science fiction,
drama film directed by Steven Spielberg.
After an encounter with UFOs, an electricity linesman feels undeniably drawn to an
isolated area in the wilderness where something spectacular is about to happen.
Roy Neary, played by Richard Dreyfuss.
Claude Lacombe, played by François Truffaut.
Ronnie Neary, played by Teri Garr.
Jillian Guiler, played by Melinda Dillon.
David Laughlin, played by Bob Balaban.
Project Leader, played by J. Patrick McNamara.
Close Encounters of the Third Kind is a 1977 American science fiction drama film written and directed by Steven
Spielberg, starring Richard Dreyfuss, Melinda Dillon, Teri Garr, Bob Balaban, Cary Guffey, and François Truffaut.
The film depicts the story of Roy Neary, an everyday blue-collar worker in Indiana, whose life changes after an encounter with an unidentified
flying object (UFO), and Jillian Guiler, a single mother whose three-year-old son Barry is abducted during the same UFO manifestation.
Close Encounters was a long-cherished project for Spielberg.
In late 1973, he developed a deal with Columbia
Pictures for a science-fiction film.
Though Spielberg received sole credit for the script, he was assisted by Paul Schrader, John Hill, David Giler, Hal
Barwood, Matthew Robbins, and Jerry Belson, all of whom contributed to the screenplay in varying degrees.
The title is derived from astronomer and Ufologist J.
Allen Hynek's classification of close encounters with extraterrestrials, in which the third
kind denotes human observations of extraterrestrials or "animate beings".
Douglas Trumbull served as the visual effects supervisor,
while Carlo Rambaldi designed the aliens.
Made on a production budget of US$19.4 million, Close Encounters was released in a limited number of
cities on November 16 and 23, 1977, and expanded into wide release the following month.
It was a critical and financial success, eventually grossing over $300 million worldwide and becoming
the third highest-grossing film of 1977 behind only Star Wars and Smokey and the Bandit.
It received numerous awards and nominations at the 50th Academy Awards, 32nd British Academy Film Awards, the 35th
Golden Globe Awards and the 5th Saturn Awards, and has been widely acclaimed by the American Film Institute.
In December 2007, it was deemed "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant" by the United
States Library of Congress and selected for preservation in the National Film Registry.
A Special Edition was released theatrically in 1980.
Spielberg agreed to create this edition to add more scenes that they had been unable to include in the original release,
with the studio demanding a controversial scene depicting the interior of the extraterrestrial mothership.
Spielberg's dissatisfaction with the altered ending scene led to a third version, the
Director's Cut on VHS and LaserDisc in 1998 (and later DVD and Blu-ray).
It is the longest version, combining Spielberg's favorite elements from both
previous editions but removing the scenes inside the mothership.
The film was later remastered in 4K and was then re-released in theaters on
September 1, 2017, by Sony Pictures Releasing for its 40th anniversary.
The film explores themes of wyoming, usa, indiana, usa, flying
saucer, extraterrestrial technology, obsession.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.